Guide to the Ronald Vance Papers MSS.454
Fales Library and Special Collections
Ronald Vance Papers
1968-1985
Fales Library and Special Collections
Vance, Ronald
MSS.454
1 Linear Feet in 1 record carton
Ronald Vance is an artist and writer active in the United States and Europe during the later half of the 20th century. This collection consists of correspondence, as well as published and unpublished writings by Vance from the late 1960s through the mid 1980s. Works of fiction present in the collection were published in literary journals including Sun and Moon, Not Guilty Magazine, and Interstate Magazine. The collection also includes unpublished writings, including notes and drafts related to Vance's I Went to Italy and Ate Chocolate.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of correspondence, as well as published and unpublished writings by Ronald Vance from the late 1960s through the mid 1980s. Works of fiction present in the collection were published in literary journals including Sun and Moon, Not Guilty Magazine, and Interstate Magazine. The collection also includes unpublished writings, including notes and drafts related to Vance's I Went to Italy and Ate Chocolate.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Biographical / Historical
Ronald Vance is an artist and writer active during the 1960s through the 1980s. He was born in Connecticut and graduated from Yale University before lecturing on the history of art at Leicester College of Art and then moving to Italy. As of May 2016, he was living in Long Island and was retired.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Ronald Vance in May 2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2016.023.
Literature, Experimental.; Artists' writings
- Benzene Editions: The Nothing Issue Part One, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Ochiishi Postcard, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Ronald Vance: Photos, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Vance W Bob Wilson, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Deem: Art and Artists, London (Ronald Vance), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Zone: Words by Ronald Vance, 1968-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- X Journal: "Field Notes", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- X Journal: "Say It's a Chair", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Dinner for Eight", 1968-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Ray Johnson Mail Art, Correspondance School, 1968-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Practice In Theory: Ray Johnson, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Sun & Moon: "Canoeing/ Body Type, Rivers, Maryland", 1968-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Sun & Moon: "Speed Reading", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Sun & Moon: "New Yet to Be", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Sun & Moon: "Bruna Sevini" (with George Deem), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Snappy Stanzas: "Heigh! Heigh Ho!mocentric", 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Oyez Review: "Bad Cheat", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Oyez Review: "Even in Spain, a Love Story", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- O.ARS Series: Toward a New Poetics (Per/Ception), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- NRG Zine, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- NGR Zine: Her Own Self, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- NGR Zine: Plastic Sense Returns, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- NRG Zine: Eyes Now in Sight, 1968-1985 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Not Guilty Mag: Core Tune Ease, 1968-1985 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Interstate: Loris Essary, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Interstate: "Sonnets and Such", 1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Interstate: "Just as Through the Same Of", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Epoch Magazine: George Henry Freedman, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Cumberland Journal: A Fallcious Belief, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Cumberland Journal: Geroge Myers Jr. (Correspondence), 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Home Gardeners Guide to Bulbs and Flowers, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Ear Magazine: Paragraph for George Deem, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Clown War, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Clown War and By Now, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Clown War: "The Underrated Bestseller", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Monday Mornings, 1972-1981 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Monday Mornings: Benzene, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- I Went to Italy and Ate Chocolate, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 40, Folder 38)
- The Home Gardener's Guide to Bulb Flowers, 1967-1974 (Box 1, Folder 39)